<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DataWorks UK</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DataWorks UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday NFL data</title>
      <link>/post/tidy-tuesday-nfl-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/tidy-tuesday-nfl-data/</guid>
      <description>Did the best team win the Superbowl?
Armed with the Tidy Tuesday data from NFL seasons back to 2000 I set out to answer the question above. With a rudimentary metric assessing the team strength based on margin of victory and strength of schedule. I created a quick data viz showing that less than third of the time the team ranked top by this metric has won the superbowl
The viz Using the ggimage package to bring a bit of Lombardi glitz to the data viz and a little bit of data wrangling to rank and join the superbowl winners with the top ranked team data gave us this output</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m Paul Nice when I&#39;m not playing cricket or being a Dance Dad to my 2 amazing daughters I love nothing else that diggin into some data to find some interesting nuggets and paint some beautiful dataviz stories. I currently work in the UK telecoms sector using data to answer the questions of what will tomorrow bring and how can we plan for it better. I spend lots of time working with timeseries data, automating data collection routines and crunching data from multiple different data sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidy Tuesday Spotify data</title>
      <link>/posts/tt-spotify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/tt-spotify/</guid>
      <description>This weeks Tidy Tuesday challenge centred around Spotify data, over 32,000 songs from multiple genres from the 60s to today. Given this was my first Tidy Tuesday for a while I decided to go for something relatively quick and simple to try to get back into the habit and look at the popularity of different types of music over time.
  Code Having read in the data the next step was to make a quick modification to allow me to work with dates as opposed to character values.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hyde-hyde</title>
      <link>/portfolio/hyde-hyde/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/portfolio/hyde-hyde/</guid>
      <description>Hyde-hyde is a responsive Hugo theme inspired by @spf13&#39;s Hyde and its variant Nate Finch&#39;s blog. It was heavily restructured with modularised page layouts for easier maintenance and modification. Hyde-hyde offers awesome features such as nice colour tone, code highlighting, Font-Awesome 5&#39;s sidebar icons), a cool portfolio page, more choices for commenting (e.g. GraphComment, Disqus).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>